Guide to the Cornell University Library miscellaneous correspondence, 1872-1944.
Cornell University Library miscellaneous correspondence, 1872-1944.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Library miscellaneous correspondence, 1872-1944.
13-1-501
Cornell University. Library.
.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Primarily correspondence of Cornell Librarians George William Harris, Willard Austen, and Otto Kinkeldey concerning such routine library matters as requests for information, receipts for books, donations, and other business. Also, miscellaneous correspondence of Woodford Patterson, Alber William Smith, David Fletcher Hoy, Justin Winsor, and letters to the C.U. Board of Trustees and faculty members. Some correspondence relates to the Fiske collections.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Primarily correspondence of Cornell Librarians George William Harris, Willard Austen, and Otto Kinkeldey concerning such routine library matters as requests for information, receipts for books, donations, and other business. Also, miscellaneous correspondence of Woodford Patterson, Alber William Smith, David Fletcher Hoy, Justin Winsor, and letters to the C.U. Board of Trustees and faculty members. Some correspondence relates to the Fiske collections.
INDEX OF CORRESPONDENCE
May 9, 1874
To John D. Van Buren, Esq., NYC; from J.L. Morris, Sibley College
May 11, 1874
Reply on same sheet of paper: to Prof. J.L. Morris; from John D. Van Buren
Mar. 16, 1875
To ?; from G.W. Schuyler
Dec. 29, 1890
To Mr. R. Arrowsmith; from Benjamin Ide Wheeler
Sept. 9, 1892
To ?; from C.R. Corson
Oct. 14, 1892
To ?; from Herbert Tuttle
Jan. 12, 1894
To Prof. Prentiss; from V.A. Moore
Nov. 21, 1895
To ?; from C.R. Corson
Sept. 22, 1898
To Honorable S.D. Halliday, Ithaca, N.Y. (Board of Trustees); from ADW, USA, Embassy, Berlin
Nov. 4, 1898
To Fred W. Ely, Esq.; from Franklin C. Cornell
Dec. 16, 1899
To Mr. Phileo; from Moses Coit Tyler
Apr. 23, 1900
To Walter P. Cook; from Franklin C. Cornell
Apr. 8, 1910
To R.C. Edlund; from Frank Irvine
Nov. 19, 1912
To Miss Carman, Presidents' Asst. Sec'y; from Bessie DeWitt Beahan
June 9, 1913
To E.L. Williams, Esq., CU; from Ralph C.H. Cattarall
Mar. 11, 1916
To Snider; from Frank S. Barton
Nov. 16, 1916
To Mr. George C. Boldt, Esq., NYC; from Willard Straight
May 8, 1918
To Prof. Charles L. Durham, Ithaca; from Frank Irvine
Oct. 14, 1918
To ?; from W.P. Van Ness
June 24, 1919
To Dr. Van Engeln; from John C. Branner
Mar. 11, 1922
To Prof. W.A. Hammond; from E.R. Corson
Feb. 26, 1932
To Mrs. Frank H. Severance; from Mary E. Cornell
Sept. 27, 1920
To Prof. Smith; from Mary E. Cornell
Oct. 15, 1934
To Dr. Otto Kinkelday; from Livingston Farrand
Letters to the Board of Trustees and Faculty
Nov. 7, 1892
From Francis T. Walker (?), Pres. of M.I.T.
Nov. 7, 1892
Cyrus Northrop, Pres. of Univ. of Minnesota
Nov. 10, 1892
Henry M. Kerr
Sept. 22, 1898
Andrew D. White to S.D. Halliday re: adding a Memorial Apse to Sage Chapel
Letters of Dr. Otto Kinkeldey
Feb. 10, 1936
From A.B. Carman
Mar. 6, 1934
Note from Woodford Patterson
Feb. 10, 1936
From Typescript copy of letter from Livingston Farrand to Kinkeldey and Miss Otis
Nov. 28, 1932
From Woodford Patterson
Sept. 11, 1931
From Albert Nordell
May 8, 1934
From Percy MacKaye
Sept. 16, 1931
Part of carbon of a reply sent to Mr. Albert Mordell
July 28, 1932
From R.L. Turner
Letters of Woodford Patterson
Apr. 5, 1934
From Rufus M. Jones
Feb. 14, 1934
From H.A. Wallace
Nov. 25, 1932
From Dr. Luzerne Coville
Apr. 8, 1913
From M.G. Menocal
Sept. 21, 1911
From Robert W. [?]
Oct. 15, 1921
From Nathan L. Miller
Letters of Geo. W. Harris
Dec. 24, 1879
From Justin Winsor
Apr. 8, 1884
From James Hall
Nov. 12, 1884
From G. Billings
Mar. 9, 1885
From Robert Fletcher
July 25, 1885
From P.H. Perkins
Aug. 20, 1885
From Sarah K. Bolton
Nov. 17, 1885
From J.W. Dwight
Dec. 31, 1885
From R.C. Davis (sent to treasurer but referred to Library?)
Jan. 7, 1886
From William E. Foster
Jan. 26, 1886
From Wm. C. Lane
Feb. 25, 1886
From R.B. Hayes
Feb. 27, 1886
From James F. Gluck
Mar. 18, 1886
From Justin Winsor
Mar. 23, 1886
From Frank P. Smith
Mar. 23, 1886
From J.N. Larned
Mar. 25, 1886
From Justin Winsor
Mar. 25, 1886
From W.C. Beehler
May 18, 1886
From L.O. Howard
May 29, 1886
From W. Belastien
June 30, 1886
From Melvil Dewey (carbon)
July 7, 1886
From H. Carrington Bolton
July 15, 1886
From C (?). B. Tillinghast
July 13, 1886
From H. Carrington Bolton
July 15, 1886
From H. Carrington Bolton
Aug. 24, 1886
From Geo. H. Baker
Sept. 23, 1886
From Wilberforce Eames
Sept. 27, 1886
From F. Saunders
Oct. 23, 1886
From F. Saunders
Aug. 8, 1886
From (?)
Jan. 13, 1887
From Henry Carrington Bolton
Jan. 26, 1887
From R.W. Selby
Mar. 1, 1888
From W.F. Poole
Mar. 17, 1888
From John S. Billings
Sept. 18, 1888
From Wm. I. Fletcher
Sept. 22, 1888
From Fred A. Halsey
Nov. 7, 1888
From J.C. Arthur
Nov. 13, 1888
From Andrew D. White
Dec. 15, 1888
From E.M. Thompson
Jan. 21, 1889
From J.N. Larned
Jan. 21, 1889
From J.A. Luitners
Feb. 1, 1889
From H.N. VanDyke
Feb. 6, 1889
From Fred V. Coville
Mar. 20, 1889
From C.C. Soule
Mar. 24, 1890
From Frank Hiscock
Mar. 27, 1890
From H. Schmidt Warterberg
Mar. 29, 1890
From Geo. T. Little
Apr. 4, 1890
From John C. Branner
Apr. 15, 1890
From Regis Chauveuet
Apr. 18, 1890
From Samuel S. Green
Apr. 19, 1890
From John Parker
May 10, 1890
From J. Billings
Sept. 27, 1890
From C.A. Cutter
Nov. 14, ?
From T.W. Rhys Davids
Photograph of Clark Bell
May 25, 1890
From W.A. Borden
Sept. 10, 1890
From George P. Brett
Sept. 24, 1890
From Herbert E. Mills
Oct. 25, 1890
From J. Billings
Nov. 28, 1890
From J. Billings
Dec. 19, 1890
From J. Billings
Mar. 5, 1891
From Jos. G. Meyer
Mar. 6, 1891
From James F. Gluck
Mar. 28, 1891
From C. Alex Nelson
Aug. 2, 1891
From C. Alex Nelson
July 20, 1891
From Geo. W. Botsford
Dec. 12, 1891
From Reginald S. Faber
Mar. 9, 1892
From Reginald S. Faber
Sept. 14, 1892
From F.B. Sanborn
Jan. 28, 1893
From Jos. G. Mayer
Oct. 27, 1893
From Azariah S. Root
Nov. 20, 1893
From Justin Winsor
Jan. 18, 1894
From Charles W. Gillet
Jan. 31, 1894
From Geo. W. Ray (?)
June 9, 1894
From Dr. E. Zarncke (transferred to Harris by J.G. Schurman)
July 21, 1894
From A.W. Lied (?) (Office of the Sec'y of War)
Aug. 23, 1894
From L. Carroll Root
Jan. 8, 1895
From J. Billings
Feb. 8, 1895
From G.B. Tillinghast
May 7, 1895
From Theodore Stanton
June 19, 1895
From Charles C. Soule
Aug. 23, 1895
John De Witt Warner
Sept. 26, 1895
Henry A. Pilsbury
Oct. 25, 1895
Frank P. Hill
Dec. 12, 1895
Geo. H. Baker
Dec. 1, 1895
James E. Russell
Feb. 18, 1896
Clinton D. Smith
Feb. 21, 1896
Eliot Temple (?) (Univ. of Michigan)
Feb. 27, 1896
M. Carey Thomas
May 1, 1896
R.C. Davis
June 3, 1896
John De Witt Warner
Jan. 11, 1897
Melvil Dewey
Apr. 2, 1897
James F. Gluck
Apr. 8, 1897
Wm. Elliot Griffis
Apr. 29, 1897
J.C. Branner
May 15, 1897
Andrew D. White
May 29, 1897
Geo. W. Davis
Apr. 26, 1897
M. Carey Thomas (letterhead and signature)
?
M. Carey Thomas (signature)
June 29, 1897
L. Carroll Root
Aug. 5, 1897
Cyrus Adler
Aug. 11, 1897
Wm. C. Lane
Sept. 29, 1897
Nathaniel Schmidt
Oct. 18, 1897
Herbert Putnam
Oct. 22, 1897
Herbert Putnam
Oct. 29, 1897
Wm. Elliot Griffis
Dec. 20, 1897
F.A. Crandall
Jan. 22, 1898
Herbert H. Smith
Mar. 9, 1898
Katherine L. Sharp
Mar. 26, 1898
R.G. Thwaites
Apr. 13, 1898
G.A. (or G.U.?) Hay
May 5, 1898
William E. Foster
May 10, 1898
J.C. Williams
May 12, 1898
Samuel S. Green
May 19, 1898
Wm. C. Lane
Sept. 15, 1898
D. Berghoffer (in German)
Oct. 15, 1898
Wallis B. Waterman
?
W.B. Waterman
Nov. 18, 1898
C.D. Wierncod (?)
Feb. 14, 1899
L. Leonetti
Apr. 1, 1899
Leo Wiener (letter addressed to Theo. W. Koch; tranferred to Library ?)
July 22, 1899
F.B. Sanborn
Sept. 26, 1899
Georgiana Guild
Jan. 9, 1900
John S. Billings
Jan. 31, 1900
Rutherford P. Hayes
Feb. 13, 1900
James H. Canfield
Feb. 20, 1900
C.K. Bolton
Mar. 14, 1900
Jacques Rosenthal
Apr. 9, 1900
Stephen D. Peet
Apr. 11, 1900
L.T. Brownell
Apr. 30, 1900
James L. Whitney
June 5, 1900
Wm. H. Brett
July 5, 1900
Albert E. Maltby
Aug. 21, 1900
Philip C. Knapp
Sept. 12, 1900
Geo. H. Fisher
Sept. 28, 1900
J. Harper (?) Jr.
Nov. 1, 1900
Prof. H.A. Rinnert
Jan. 22, 1901
A.B. Kruger
May 16, 1901
James H. Canfield
June 2, 1901
H(?).W. Halsey
June 5, 1901
Louis Wilson
June 13, 1901
N.D.C. Hodges
June 26, 1901
Sidney R. Greenstadt
July 2, 1901
Sidney R. Greenstadt
Sept. 21, 1901
Louis Wilson
Sept. 21, 1901
M.M. Chabert
Oct. 5, 1901
J.C. Branner
Nov. 26, 1901
M. Barbi (?) (in Italian)
Dec. 10, 1901
From Charles G. Osgood
Dec. 13, 1901
From C.E. Norton
Dec. 22, 1901
From Charles G. Osgood
Dec. 27, 1901
From C.E. Norton
Aug. 28, 1902
From William Beer
Sept. 21, 1903
From Herbert H. Smith (?)
Oct. 9, 1903
From James H. Canfield
Feb. 15, 1904
From William Beer
Jan. 22, 1906
From E. Chatelain
Jan. 24, 1908
From H. Wadlin
Feb. 1, 1908
From C.H. Gould
Jan. 26, 1909
From H. Black
Jan. 25, 1910
From Mrs. Jourois (?)
Oct. 4, 1911
From Horatio C. King
Miscellaneous correspondence
Sept. 21, 1863
Copy (?) of statement by John M. Harlan, Attorney General of Kentucky (transf. to Mss. 6-1-83)
Apr. 9, 1840
From Antonio Blitz, prestidigitateur; to Furman, American Museum (transf. to Mss. 6-1-83)
Aug. 26, 1897
From Erhard Zarnicke (?) (also memo from C.U.L. in re: the Zarncke collection); to ?
Oct. 24, 1904
From W. Osler; to ?
Apr. 15, 1908
From Announcement of the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission
Jan. 9, 1911
From Julius Kahn; to Wm. Poillon
Dec. 22, 1916
Clipping from Boston Evening Transcript, regarding Harvard's acquisition of a Sargent landscape
Calling card of Louis H. Ayme, Consul of the U.S.A.
July 12, ?
From J. Bryce; to J.G. Schurman
Biographical sketch (printed) of William Daniel
Feb. 10, 1836
From M. Faraday; to ?
Pamphlet - "The Bank Restriction Barometer" - relating to the English Bank Notes
Series of bound documents concerning Prof. Zarncke
May 23, 1774
Photostatic and printed copies of letter from Isaac Low to the Committee of Correspondence in Boston
Autograph letter of Seymour Haden
?
Fragment of letter from Daniel Gilman; to ?
?
Note from (?) Mazzini; to ?
Empty envelope upon which is written "A.L.S. from Hiram Corson to Miss Charlotte Porter, Browning Scholar and Editor of Poet Lore."
July 11, 1887
From H.B. Brown; to B.W. Austin
Feb. 14, 1889
From Stevenson Burke; to B.W. Austin
May 17, 1890
From William Daniel; to B.W. Austin
June 20, 1894
From Jas. G. Field; to B.W. Austin
Letters of Acting President Albert W. Smith
Signature of M.L. Burton
Aug. 23, 1921
From A. Lawrence Lorrell
Sept. 7, 1921
From M.L. Burton
Sept. 4, 1921
From John Grier Hibben
Oct. 3, 1921
From James Rowland Angell
Aug. 23, 1921
From James Rowland Angell
Sept. 12, 1921
From Charles W. Eliot
Letters of Registrar (David Hoy)
Jan. 26, 1912
From Jacob H. Schiff
Apr. 8, 1898
From Wilberforce Eames
Nov. 21, 1904
From M.L. Bruce [?]
Aug. 26, 1908
From Walt C. Murray
Apr. 9, 1920
From Elbridge T. Gerry
Letters of Willard H. Austen
May 17, 1890
From D. Nicholson
Aug. 25, 1890
From Geo. S. Spinney
Aug. 27, 1890
From T.R. Learned (?)
Feb. 9, 1891
From W.F. Poole
July 19, 1893
From Robert Adler Bowen
Jan. 22, 1894
From A. Smith (?) Warner
Feb. 13, 1897
From Eleanor A. Grmerod (?)
Nov. 2, 1898
From W.I. Fletcher
Jan. 21, 1899
From Jeannette L. Gilder
Jan. 25, 1899
From G.H. Putnam
Feb. 10, 1899
From Jeannette L. Gilder
Apr. 25, 1899
From Melville D. Landon
Jan. 9, 1900
From J. Gilder
Nov. 6, 1907
From E.C. Richardson
Mar. 12, 1908
From J.H. Kellogg
May 11, 1908
From Goodwin Brown
Feb. 10, 1909
From G.E. Woodbury (or Woodberry?)
June 25, 1909
From Leander T. Chamberlain
Aug. 25, 1909
From Ben B. Lindsey
Aug. 30, 1909
From Maud B. Booth
July 3, 1910
Document from the American Embassy in Rome (in Italian), with a note from President Schurman
July 30, 1912
From Andrew D. White
Aug. 2, 1916
From Edward S. Curtis
Aug. 11, 1916
From Thomas S. Jones, Jr.
Sept. 23, 1916
From Katherine B. Judson
Mar. 2, 1917
From Thomas Hagan
Apr. 26, 1917
From Charles F. Prentice
July 14, 1917
From Vernon Watney
Dec. 7, 1917
From Andrew D. White
Dec. 8, 1917
From W.K. Bixby
Mar. 27, 1918
From James Vincent Nash
Mar. 29, 1918
From Worthington C. Ford
Oct. 1, 1918
From F. Madan
Feb. 18, 1920
From H.A. Wilson
June 20, 1920
From David Chalmers Nimmo
June 22, 1920
From Lord Channing
1921
From Dr. Paul Cohn (postcard)
Apr. 9, 1921
From Dr. Paul Cohn
Apr. 22, 1921
From Charles M. Harrington
May 7, 1921
From A. (?). Sedles (?) (Sec'y's office, Yale Univ.)
Mar. 16, 1922
From S. James
Mar. 21, 1922
From John B. Stetson Jr.
Apr. 18, 1922
From William M. Calder
Aug. 21, 1922
From John Cotton Dana
Aug. 22, 1922
From Pio Rajira (?) (in Italian)
Sept. 16, 1922
From Sao-Ke (?) Alfred Sze
Oct. 23, 1922
From Frederick Parsons
Oct. 30, 1922
From John R. Mott
Jan. 27, 1923
From Grant Overton
Feb. 5, 1923
From Norman J. Gould
Feb. 27, 1923
From T.J.J. See
Mar. 30, 1923
From Wm. Sulzer
Apr. 24, 1923
From George Wallingford Noyes
Aug. 20, ?
From William Elliot Griffis
Oct. 4, 1923
From William Elliot Griffis
Apr. 27, 1923
From Henry Gappr (?)
May 11, 1923
From L.D. Barnett (?)
Aug. 29, 1923
From J. Franklin Jameson
Nov. 12, 1923
From (?). MountNephew (?)
June 17, 1924
From Kate Stephens
Feb. 7, 1925
From Rex F. Harlow
Apr. 20, 1925
From A.H. Stocking
May 14, 1925
From Ramon Coffman
Aug. 10, 1925
From Lucy M. Salmon
Apr. 28, 1926
From M.K. Farrand
Apr. 28, 1926
From Frank Pierrepont Graves
Aug. 19, 1926
From Wm. Elliot Griffis
Sept. 18, 1926
From Elizabeth Hutcher Sadler
Sept. 9, 1926
From C.D. Cook
Nov. 5, 1926
From E.T. Nash
Feb. 24, 1927
From Viscount Knutsford
Feb. 4, 1927
From Francis Griffin Stokes
Feb. 22, 1927
From Francis Griffin Stokes
June 7, 1927
From Woodford Patterson
June 16, 1928
From Demetrius C. Boulger
July 7, 1928
From Demetrius C. Boulger
July 21, 1928
From Albert Bushnell Hart
Mar. 28, 1930
From Thomas Hagan
May 22, (?)
From Kirk Munroe
Aug. 31, (?)
From Henry Vignaue
(?)
Fragment of letter from J.O. Vincent
Calling card of Thomas O'Hagan
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Library.; Austen, Willard.; Harris, George William.; Hoy, David Fletcher.; Kinkeldey, Otto, 1878-1966.; Patterson, Woodford, 1870-1948.; Hu, Shi, 1891-1962.; Smith, Albert William.; Winsor, Justin, 1831-1897.; Cornell University.Board of Trustees.
Subjects:
Academic libraries--New York (State)--Ithaca.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- 1872-1885 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1886-1887 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1888-1889 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1890-1891 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1982-1893 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1894 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1895-1897 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1897-1898 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1899-1900 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1901 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 1902-1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1910-1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Includes list of books presented to Cornell University Library by Chinese students, Dec. 28, 1911 and letters from Hu Shih.
- 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 1926-1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)